George Evans Papers 1998.0341
Archives & Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center, University of Connecticut Libraries
George Evans Papers, Charles Olson/ Cid Corman Correspondence
undated, 1931-1991.
1998.0341
Archives & Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center, University of Connecticut Libraries
3.0 Linear feet
Born in 1948 in Pittsburgh, Evans is a widely published poet currently living in San Francisco. He has published three collections of poetry in England: Nightvision, Wrecking, and Eye Blade. His poetry has been featured twice in Origin.
Evans, George, 1948-.
Biography
Born in 1948 in Pittsburgh, George Evans is a widely published poet currently living in San Francisco, CA. He received his M.A. from Johns Hopkins University and has been the recipient of a writing fellowship from the National Endowment for the Arts, and a research fellowship from the Japan ese government Monbusho for the study of Japanese poetry. He has published three collections of poetry in England: Nightvision, Wrecking, and Eye Blade. His poetry has been featured twice in Origin.
Scope and Content
The collection consists of correspondence between the author and several individuals as well as photocopies of the correspondence between Charles Olson and Cid Corman. Also included are manuscript, typescript, and proofs of Charles Olson & Cid Corman: Complete Correspondence, 1950-1964 [Dodd C5032]. The bulk of the materials date from 1983 until 1987.
Arrangement
Series I: Correspondence ( nd., 1981-1991 )
Series II: Charles Olson & Cid Corman: Complete Correspondence, 1950-1964, ( undated, 1950-1987 )
Series III: Published materials ( undated, 1931-1991 )
Related Material
Archives & Special Collections has a substantial collection of literary materials, especially those associated with Black Mountain College, Charles Olson and the Beat Generation Poets. For detailed information on these collections please contact the curator or ask at the reference desk.
Restrictions on Access
Permission to copy and/or publish materials from the collection MUST be obtained from the appropriate institution or individual.
Originals of the materials are located in the following literary collections:
Harry Ransom Humanities Research Center, University of Texas, Austin; Thomas J. Dodd Research Center, University of Connecticut.
Acquisition Information
The collection was purchased in 1998.
Author.; Authors, American—20th century—Correspondence.; Corman, Cid—Correspondence.; Correspondence.; Manuscripts.; Olson, Charles, 1910-1970. -Correspondence.; Olson, Charles, 1910-1970. Charles Olseon & Cid Corman: complete correspondence, 1950-1964.; Photocopies.; Poets, American—20th century—Correspondence.; Publications.; Typescripts.
- Series I: Correspondence, undated, 1981-1991
  - Chronological, 1984-1990 (Box 1:, Folder 1)
  - Butterick, George / Glover, Albert, 1983 (Box 1:, Folder 2)
  - Evans, George / Alpert, Marie, 1985-1991 (Box 1:, Folder 3)
  - Evans, George / Butterick, George, 1981-1983 (Box 1:, Folder 4)
  - Evans, George / Butterick, George, 1983 (Box 1:, Folder 5)
  - Evans, George / Butterick, George, 1984 (Box 1:, Folder 6)
  - Evans, George / Butterick, George, 1984-1988 (Box 1:, Folder 7)
  - Evans, George / Creeley, Robert, 1983 (Box 1:, Folder 8)
  - Evans, George / Glover, Albert, 1983 (Box 1:, Folder 9)
  - Evans, George / Terrell, C. F., 1982-1987 (Box 1:, Folder 10)
  - Olson/Corman book Cover Art, 1986-1988 (Box 1:, Folder 11)
  - Search File, 1981-1984 (Box 1:, Folder 12)
  - Unidentified notes and papers, 1985-1986 (Box 1:, Folder 13)
- Series II: Charles Olson & Cid Corman: Complete Correspondence, 1950-1964, undated, 1950-1987
  - Collated copies of Olson/Corman letters, 1950-1951 (Box 6:, Folder 51)
  - Collated copies of Olson/Corman letters, 1951-1952 (Box 6:, Folder 52)
  - Collated copies of Olson/Corman letters, 1952-1953 (Box 6:, Folder 53)
  - Collated copies of Olson/Corman letters, 1953-1964 (Box 6:, Folder 54)
  - MS front matter, Introduction and notes, undated (Box 6:, Folder 55)
  - MS footnotes (both volumes), undated (Box 6:, Folder 56)
  - Volume I (Box 1:)
    - Original TS: front matter, introduction appendices (pp. Cover-100), undated (Box 1:, Folder 14)
    - Original TS (pp. 101-199), undated (Box 1:, Folder 15)
    - Original TS (pp. 200-269), undated (Box 1:, Folder 16)
    - Original TS (pp. 270-597, blank), undated (Box 1:, Folder 17)
    - Original TS with ms corrections (photocopy, pp. 1-122), undated (Box 2:, Folder 18)
    - Original TS with ms corrections (photocopy, pp. 123-226), undated (Box 2:, Folder 19)
    - Original TS with ms corrections (photocopy, pp. 227-349), undated (Box 2:, Folder 20)
    - Original TS with ms corrections (photocopy, pp. 350-544), undated (Box 2:, Folder 21)
    - Footnotes: TS, corrected, undated (Box 2:, Folder 22)
  - Volume I
    - Final TS with annotations (pp. 1-98), undated (Box 3:, Folder 23)
    - Final TS with annotations (pp. 99-187), undated (Box 3:, Folder 24)
    - Final TS with annotations (pp. 188-271), undated (Box 3:, Folder 25)
    - Final TS with annotations (pp. 272-330), undated (Box 3:, Folder 26)
    - Proof: corrected and rejected, undated (Box 3:, Folder 27)
    - Proof: corrected and rejected, 1985 (Box 7:, Folder 57)
    - Proofs: photocopy with corrections, undated (Box 3:, Folder 28)
    - Final proofs: corrected (photocopy, pp. 1-100), 1987 (Box 3:, Folder 29)
    - Final proofs: corrected (photocopy, pp. 101-200), 1987 (Box 3:, Folder 30)
    - Final proofs: corrected (photocopy, pp. 201-332, 2 blank), 1987 (Box 3:, Folder 31)
    - Unbound signatures (12), undated (Box 3:, Folder 32)
  - Volume II
    - Original TS (pp. 306-399), undated (Box 3:, Folder 33)
    - Original TS (pp. 400-499), undated (Box 3:, Folder 34)
    - Original TS (pp. 500-599), undated (Box 3:, Folder 35)
    - Original TS (pp. 600-659), undated (Box 3:, Folder 36)
    - Final TS with annotations (photocopy, pp. 331-423), undated (Box 4:, Folder 37)
    - Final TS with annotations (photocopy, pp. 424-510), undated (Box 4:, Folder 38)
    - Final TS with annotations (photocopy, pp.511-585), undated (Box 7:, Folder 58)
    - Final TS with annotations (photocopy, pp. 586-659), undated (Box 7:, Folder 59)
    - Proof: rejected, undated (Box 4:, Folder 39-41)
    - Proof used for indexing (pp. 11-107), undated (Box 4:, Folder 42)
    - Proof used for indexing (pp. 108-186), undated (Box 4:, Folder 43)
    - Paste up (photocopy, pp.1-110), undated (Box 4:, Folder 44)
    - Paste up (photocopy, pp. 111-168), undated (Box 4:, Folder 45)
- Series III: Published materials, undated, 1931-1991
  - Charles Olson & Cid Corman: Complete Correspondence, 1950-1964, edited by George Evans, two volumes (Orono, Maine: National Poetry Foundation, University of Maine, 1987, 1991. (Box 5:)
    - Volume I with corrections, 1987 (Box 5:, Folder 46)
    - Volume II with corrections, 1991 (Box 5:, Folder 47)
  - Introduction to Dogtown by M. McClure (photocopy), undated (Box 5:, Folder 48)
  - Origin Spring issue, 1951 (Box 5:, Folder 49)
  - Origin, v. X, 1953 (Box 7:, Folder 60)
  - Poetry, v. XXXVII, no. V (photocopy, Objectivist issue), 1931 (Box 5:, Folder 50)